Guide to The Banded Geckos collection, 1980-2017 MS 681
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
The Banded Geckos collection
1980-2017
1980-2000
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Taylor, Evelyne
MS 681
1.5 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 1 map drawer)
This collection consists of photographs, news clippings, promotional materials, and audio.
Biographical / Historical
The Banded Geckos formed in 1979. The original line-up consisted of Fred McDonough, Tim Taylor, and Evelyne Taylor. After McDonough left the band in 1981, Russell Fory and Gary Young joined. Over the course of 1983 into 1984, the band recorded their first album at Loma Ranch Studios in Fredericksburg, TX, entitled "The Banded Geckos."
After Gary Young moved on, Fory and the Taylors continued as a trio. With the addition of Charlie Arruda in 1988, the band recorded "Gecko Greetings," a Christmas album. They began work on "Art Gecko" in 1989, releasing it in 1990. In 1992, Arruda moved to Pennsylvania and Robert Knetsch joined the band.
In 1993, the Taylors relocated to Santa Fe, New Mexico and began recording "Gecoupage" in 1994 with Russell Fory, Robert Knetsch, Grey Howell, and Pat Longmire, releasing it in 1995. In 2000, the Taylors and Grey Howell released "Gecko Canyon."
Over the years, The Banded Geckos performed at the Kerrville Folk Festival, Anderson Fair, Mucky Duck, Uncle Calvin's, Cactus Cafe and other venues throughout Texas, New Mexico, and beyond.
Scope and Contents
This collections consists of photographs, news clippings, promotional materials, audio, and other items chronicling the musical history of The Banded Geckos.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Evelyne Taylor in February 2017.
Related Materials
Please see the Rice University KTRU Radio records, UA 011.
Accruals
No additional materials are expected for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects
Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Music
Document Types
Folk music
- Series I: General files
  - Biography, 1985-2017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera, 1980s-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fliers, 1980s-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Gecko Echo", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Gecko Greetings" art and information, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News clippings, 1984-2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1980-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Promotion, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Audio
  - "The Banded Geckos" 12" LP (2), 1984 (Box 1)
  - "Gecko Greetings" unmastered CD, 1988 (Box 1)
  - "Art Gecko" CD, 1990 (Box 1)
  - "Gecoupage", 1995 (Box 1)
  - "The Banded Geckos: 15th Year Anniversary 1999 Re-issue" (Box 1)
  - "Gecko Canyon", 2000 (Box 1)
- Series III: Oversized
  - Fliers, 1981-1990s (Box 2)
  - Art - three geckos, 1980s (Box 2)
  - Photograph, 1990 (Box 2)
  - "The Banded Geckos: The Album" T-shirt, 1984 (Box 2)
  - "Art Gecko" T-shirt (2), 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kerrville Folk Festival posters (4), 1982-1985 (Map-drawer 196, Item 7-10)